NELSON TORRES

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

(615)997-4743

NelsonTorresJr330@gmail.com

https://github.com/Nelsontorresjr330

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ nelsontorresjr330/

PREVIOUS PROJECTS

Civilization Simulation in Python (CS5260

Image Processor for Android in Java (CS5253 - Parallel Programming) Snake in C++ for Arduino (Personal Project)

Tkinter Personal Calender using Google API in Python (Perosonal Project)

EDUCATION

Master of Science

Vanderbilt University

2023-2024

3.74 GPA - Computer Science Major Notable Coursework : Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Model-Based Development, Computer Networks, Parallel Programming

Bachelor of Science

Middle Tennessee State University

2018 - 2022

3.45 GPA - Computer Engineering & Applied Physics Double Major Notable Coursework: Discrete Structures and Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Circuit Design, Microprocessor Design, Programming Language Design, Assembly and Computer Design

PROFILE

I am an MTSU Graduate with a B.S. in Computer Engineering & Applied Physics (Computer Science Concentration) & a French Minor. My expertise revolves around database management, ETL work, and SQL development in part due to the Vanderbilt University Data Analytics Bootcamp. I am currently working as a Full-Stack Software Engineer at IPro Systems & am also a student at Vanderbilt University working towards my Master's in Computer Science.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Engineer

IPro Systems

Nov 2022 - Present

- Develop and debug backend APIs and frontend UI/UX changes
- Worked with Python, Boto3, Docker, Java, SQL, FastAPI, AGILE, Node.JS, Spark and AWS
- Notable projects: AWS Redshift DDL, Massive ETL of Tenant from legacy systems, Pytest coverage increases

Controls Engineer Intern

Automation NTH

Aug 2022 - Nov 2022

- Went through the NTH University program as an Intern to prepare working as a Controls Engineer for the organization
- Programming PLCs, Desiging schematics & electrical diagrams via AutoCAD, Constructing & wiring panels.

Contractor / Data Manager

J&N Carpentry

May 2020 - Aug 2022

- · Creating VBA scripts to automate document creation
- Managed SQL DB to handle sensative information
- · Managed employees and met with customers

Physics Tutor

MTSU Physics Department

Aug 2021 - Aug 2022

 Helped students understand concepts thought throughout various courses ranging from Introductory Calc-Based Physics to Modern Physics